Georgios Vavouliotis

Travessera de Les Corts 37, 08028 - Barcelona - Spain

✓ gvavou5@gmail.com • in georgios-vavouliotis • • • Gyavou5

Profile

I earned my diploma on Electrical and Computer Engineering Department of National Technical University of Athens (NTUA). During my studies, I completed numerous projects that gave me a solid background in Computer Science and Software Engineering. Currently, I am a 2nd year Ph.D. student in Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC) and Barcelona Supercomputing Center (BSC-CNS). My supervisors are Dr. Marc Casas Guix from BSC-CNS and Dr. Lluc Alvarez from UPC. Moreover, I collaborate with Prof. Daniel A. Jiménez from Texas A&M University. Finally, my research aims at building hardware predictors that inherently use artificial intelligence algorithms.

Areas of Interest

- Computer Architecture
- o Artificial Intelligence

- System Software
- Operating Systems

Education

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC)

Barcelona

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.)

September 2018-now

Leveraging Artificial Intelligence Algorithms for Hardware Prediction

National Technical University of Athens (NTUA)

Athens

Diploma on Electrical & Computer Engineering, 300 ECTS, GPA: 8.9/10

2012-March 2018

Academic Directions.....

- Computer Systems & Software
- Computer Networks and Networks Security
- Signal Processing, Automatic Control and Robotics

Diploma Thesis.....

Performance Analysis of TLB Prefetching Mechanisms, GPA: 10/10

General Lyceum, Chalkida, Greece

Chalkida

Apolytirion, Top 0.1% in National Qualification Exams, GPA: 19.5/20

2009-2012

Research Experience

Barcelona Supercomputing Center (BSC-CNS)

Barcelona

Research Student September 2018-now

Projects involved: SOW 5.3 - Intel and BSC-CNS Collaboration, High Performance Computing VII

National Technical University of Athens (NTUA)

Research Student on Computer Systems Laboratory (CSLab)

February 2018-July 2018

Participation in Projects

SOW 5.3 - Intel and BSC-CNS Collaboration

Barcelona

September 2018-now

Barcelona Supercomputing Center (BSC-CNS)

High Performance Computing VII

Barcelona

Athens

Barcelona Supercomputing Center (BSC-CNS)

September 2018-now

Publications

[1] **Georgios Vavouliotis**, Goumas Georgios, "Performance Analysis of TLB Prefetching Mechanisms". Book of my diploma thesis.

[2] **Georgios Vavouliotis**, Lluc Alvarez, Daniel A. Jimenez, Marc Casas Guix, *Cost-Effective Instruction TLB Prefetching*. Second Young Architect Workshop (YArch 2020). In conjunction with The 25th ACM International Conference on Architectural Support for Programming Languages and Operating Systems (ASPLOS 2020), Lausanne.

[3] **Georgios Vavouliotis**, Lluc Alvarez, Vasileios Karakostas, Konstantinos Nikas, Nectarios Koziris, Daniel A. Jimenez, Marc Casas Guix, *Exploiting Page Table Locality for Agile TLB Prefetching*. Submitted to 53th International Symposium on Microarchitecture (MICRO) [under review].

Seminars and Training Courses

Summer Schools

Participation in accredited Summer Schools (certification provided)

HPC Architectures for Artificial Intelligence and Dedicated Applications

Provided by **ACM-Europe**, 17 - 24 July 2019

Seminars

Participation in accredited seminars (certification provided)

Introduction to Heterogenous Memory Usage

Provided by **PACT BSC-CNS**, 26 February 2019

Online Courses (MOOCs)

Courses offered by accredited universities and training programs (certification provided)

Machine Learning

- Provided by **Stanford University** (Prof. Andrew Ng), May 2018 July 2018, **GPA: 10/10**
 - · Supervised Learning (Regression Models, SVMs, NN)
 - · Unsupervised Learning (Clustering, Dimensionality Reduction)

Advanced Programming with Python

Provided by Mathesis Online Platform, March 2018 - April 2018, GPA: 10/10

- · Object Oriented Programming
- · Data Storage (sqlite3, pickle, JSON)
- · Graphic Interface Programming and Game Development

Teaching Experience

Private Tutor Athens

During my Diploma I was giving private lectures to:

2013-2018

Undergraduate students of Computer Science Department

C programming, Computer Architecture, Operating Systems, Automatic Control

High school students

Mathematics, Physics

Lab Assistant at National Technical University of Athens (NTUA)

Athens

C programming, Operating Systems

2013-2017

Technical and Personal skills

Programming Languages:

- Proficient: C, Python, Matlab-Simulink
- Basic knowledge: C++, Octave, Java, R, Prolog, SML/NJ, Assembly (8085, 8086, AVR)

Software Skills:

- Proficient: Unix Bash, LATEX, Git, MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)
- Basic knowledge: HTML, CSS, PHP, Javascript, Cacti, TCL AWK Wireshark

o Simulators:

Proficient: ChampSimBasic knowledge: Gem5

Operating Systems:

- Proficient: Linux, Mac OS, Windows

o General Business Skills:

- Ability to work with a team
- Very good presentation skills
- Able to write well organized and structured reports

Honors and Awards

Affiliations

- Affiliated PhD student in HiPEAC (European Network of Excellence on High Performance and Embedded Arcitecture and Compilation)
- o IEEE member

Languages

- Greek (Native) English (B2 (FCE, KPG)) Spanish (Beginner)
- Personal Interests and extra-curricular activity
- Challenges Cooking Writing Basketball Cinema

References

References available upon request.